<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>celestial-revelations on erenon.hu</title>
    <link>http://erenon.hu/tags/celestial-revelations/</link>
    <description>Recent blogposts on erenon.hu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://erenon.hu/tags/celestial-revelations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The sorcerers frog</title>
      <link>http://erenon.hu/posts/2014-03-29-the-sorcerers-frog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://erenon.hu/posts/2014-03-29-the-sorcerers-frog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once there was a sorcerer who had the most shining gold. A simple and mild
man came to him and wanted to buy this gold from him. The sorcerer said to
the simple man: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You will not receive this gold, unless you give me better
gold and in larger quantity.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; The man said: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have such a great desire for
your gold that I will give you what you want rather than losing it.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; He then
gave the sorcerer better gold and in larger quantity and received the shining
gold from him and put it in a casket, thinking of making himself a ring from
it for his finger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short time, the sorcerer approached that simple man and said: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;The
gold you bought from me and laid in your casket is not gold, as you thought,
but the most ugly frog. It has been fostered in my chest and fed with my
food. And in order for you to test and know that this is true, you may
open the casket and you will see how the frog will jump to my chest
where it was fostered.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; When the man wanted to open it and find out if
it was true, the frog appeared in the casket. The cover of the casket
was hanging on four hinges that were about to break and fall off soon.
Immediately when the cover of the casket was opened, the frog saw the
sorcerer and jumped into his chest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the servants and friends of the simple man saw this, they said to him:
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Lord, this most fine gold is in the frog, and if you want, you can easily
get the gold.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; The man said: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;How can I get it?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; They replied: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;If
someone took a sharp and heated spear and thrust it into the hollow part of
the frog&amp;rsquo;s back, he would quickly get the gold out. But if he cannot find any
hollow in the frog, he should then, with the greatest force and effort,
thrust his spear into it, and this is how you will get back the gold
you bought.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Celestial Revelations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
